<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- K-Mod hints -->
	<!-- Style guidelines (from CIV4GameText_Strategy.xml): -->
	<!-- Technologies should be colored COLOR_TECH_TEXT (example: [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Bronze Working[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Unit should be colored COLOR_UNIT_TEXT (example: [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Archers[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Buildings should be colored COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT (example: [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Theatre[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Projects should be colored COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT (example: [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]SS Engine[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Anything else official (that should be capitalized) should be colored COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT (example: [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Trade Mission[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] or [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Islam[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]) -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">

<!-- advc.008c: Added "(K-Mod)" to hints that describe K-Mod changes
	(even those that are just included in K-Mod because players may not know
	that e.g. "BUG" is the name of a mod).
	I'm also putting any corrections of BtS hints into K-Mod hints.xml, so that
	CIV4GameText_advc.008d.xml only contains hints about AdvCiv changes. -->

<!-- advc.008c: Now also hints at menu button -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUG_HINT_INTERFACE_1</Tag>
	<English>You can customize the BUG mod from the game menu [ESC], or by pressing [ALT + CTRL + O].</English>
	<French>Pressez [ALT + CTRL + O] pour accèder aux écrans d'options du BUG Mod.</French>
	<German>Die BUG-Mod lässt sich vom Menü [ESC] aus konfigurieren, oder mit der Tastenkombination [STRG + ALT + O].</German>
	<Italian>Premi [ALT + CTRL + O] per accedere alla schermata di configurazione del BUG Mod.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Presiona [ALT + CTRL + O] para abrir la pantalla de opciones de BUG.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- advc.008c: Just stylistic changes -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_1</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) Aqueduct and Hospital increase a city's health, whereas Public Transportation and Recycling Center reduce its pollution.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) Aqueduct and Hospital increase a city's health, whereas Public Transportation and Recycling Center reduce its pollution.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Aquädukt und Krankenhaus erhöhen den Gesundheitswert einer Stadt, wohingegen öffentliche Verkehrsmittel und Recyclinganlagen die Umweltverschmutzung lindern.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) Un acquedotto o un ospedale aumentano la salute della città, ma il trasporto pubblico o il centro riciclaggio ne riducono l'inquinamento.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Un acueducto o un hospital aumentará la salud de una ciudad, pero el transporte público o un centro de reciclaje reduce su polución.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_2</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) The cultural influence of each city extends beyond its border. If you are being culturally pressured by another civilization, consider getting more culture in all nearby cities; not just the cities being pressed.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) The cultural influence of each city extends beyond its border. If you are being culturally pressured by another civilization, consider getting more culture in all nearby cities; not just the cities being pressed.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Der kulturelle Einfluss einer Stadt erstreckt sich über ihre Grenzen hinaus. Unter kulturellem Druck bietet es sich daher an, auch in benachbarten Städten mehr Kultur zu produzieren, nicht nur in den betroffenen Städten.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) L'influenza culturale di ogni città si estende oltre i suoi bordi. Se sei pressato culturalmente da un'altra civiltà prendi in considerazione di aumentare l'output culturale delle città vicine e non solo di quella pressata.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) La influencia clultural de cada ciudad se extiende más alla de su frontera. Si estás siendo presionado culturalmente por otra civilización, considera adquirir más cultura en todas las ciudades cercanas; no solo en las ciudades que están siendo presionadas.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- advc.008c: Qualified this one a bit. Global warming isn't normally a good
	 reason not to chop. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_3</Tag>
	<English>In the late game, forests and jungles help offset the pollution caused by your civilization. If you don't need to chop them down, consider keeping them to reduce the effects of global warming.</English>
	<French>In the late game, forests and jungles help offset the pollution caused by your civilization. If you don't need to chop them down, consider keeping them to reduce the effects of global warming.</French>
	<German>Wälder und Dschungel helfen gegen Spielende, die Umweltverschmutzung Ihrer Zivilisation auszugleichen. Ziehen Sie in Betracht, sie zu erhalten, um dem Klimawandel entgegenzuwirken.</German>
	<Italian>Foreste e giungle aiutano a contrastare l'inquinamento causato dalla tua civilità. Se non hai necessità di abbatterle, considera di mantenerle per ridurre gli effetti del riscaldamento globale.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Los bosques y las selvas ayudan a compensar la polución causada por tu civilización. Si no necesitas talarlos, considéraros para reducir los efectos del calentamiento global.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_4</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) If a rival civilization becomes fixated on world domination - beware! They may decide to attack you even if they appear friendly.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) If a rival civilization becomes fixated on world domination - beware! They may decide to attack you even if they appear friendly.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Wenn eine rivalisierende Zivilisation sich auf Weltherrschaft fixiert - vorsicht! Sie könnten sich entscheiden, Sie anzugreifen, selbst wenn sie freundlich erscheinen.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) Se una civiltà rivale punta a dominare il mondo - attenzione! Potrebbe decidere di attacacrti anche se appare amichevole.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Si un rival se ha obsesionado en la dominación mundial - ¡ten cuidado! Pueden decidir atacarte incluso si parecen amistosos.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- advc.008c: Apparently a mix-up of Assembly Line and Industrial Park-->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_5</Tag>
	<English>Factories and Industrial Parks create extra pollution with coal and oil. If you aren't using your fossil fuels, consider removing access to them so that your people will be healthier.</English>
	<French>Factories and Industrial Parks create extra pollution with coal and oil. If you aren't using your fossil fuels, consider removing access to them so that your people will be healthier.</French>
	<German>Fabriken und Industriegebiete erzeugen zusätzliche Verschmutzung mit Kohle und Öl. Benötigen Sie ihre fossilen Brennstoffe nicht, ziehen Sie in Betracht, den Zugang zu ihnen abzuschneiden, damit Ihre Bevölkerung gesünder wird.</German>
	<Italian>Fabbriche e Linee di produzione causano ulteriore inquinamento con carbone e petrolio. Se non usi combustibili fossili, considera di rimuoverne l'accesso per aumentare la salute di cittadini.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Las fábricas y cadenas de montaje pueden producir polución extra con carbón y petróleo. Si no estás usando combustibles fósiles, considera quitar el acceso a ellos para que tu gente sea más saludable.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_6</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) Units with the "leadership" warlord promotion greatly reduce the chance of cultural revolts in their city.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) Units with the "leadership" warlord promotion greatly reduce the chance of cultural revolts in their city.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Einheiten mit der "Kriegsherr"-Beförderung in Städten verringern sehr die Wahrscheinlichkeit von kulturbedingten Revolten.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) Le unità con la promozione "Leadership" (Grande Generale richiesto) riducono maggiormente le probabilità di rivolta di una città.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Las unidades con el ascendo de caudillo "liderazgo" reduce enormemente la probabilidad de rebeliones culturales en su ciudad.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_7</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) When a Great General chooses to lead a unit as a warlord, it shares an immediate experience boost to all units in the group. More experience points are given to bigger groups.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) When a Great General chooses to lead a unit as a warlord, it shares an immediate experience boost to all units in the group. More experience points are given to bigger groups.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Wenn ein Großer General sich dazu entschließt, eine Einheit als Kriegsherr zu führen, teilt er einmalig Erfahrungspunkte mit allen Einheiten der Gruppe. Größere Gruppen erhalten dabei mehr Punkte als kleine.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) Quando un Grande Generale decide di unirsi ad un unità come Grande Condottiero, distribuisce in immediato aumento di esperienza con tutte le unità sulla stessa casella. Maggiore lo stack, maggiore l'esperienza.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Cuando un Gran General elige liderar una unidad como un caudillo, comparte un aumento inmediato de experiencia a todas las unidades en el grupo. Más puntos de experiencia son dados a grupos más grandes.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- advc.008c: Just style -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_8</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) In the city screen, hold down the [ALT] key and point to a building or specialist to see its net effect.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) In the city screen, hold down the [ALT] key and point to a building or specialist to see its net effect.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Halten Sie im Stadtbildschirm [Alt] gedrückt und zeigen Sie auf ein Gebäude oder einen Spezialisten, um seinen Netto-Effekt zu sehen.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) In the city screen, hold down the [ALT] key and point to a building or specialist to see its net effect.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Mantén la tecla [ALT] presionada y apunta a un edificio o especialista para ver el efecto si estuviera en la ciudad actual.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_9</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) As religions grow older, they become slightly less likely to spread.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) As religions grow older, they become slightly less likely to spread.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Ältere Religionen verbreiten sich ein kleines bisschen langsamer.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) As religions grow older, they become slightly less likely to spread.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Cuando las religiones envejecen, se vuelven un poco menos probable de propagarse.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- advc.008c: German text was a bit misleading -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_10</Tag>
	<English>If a foreign leader is Pleased with you, they will not mind being asked for a small gift.</English>
	<French>If a foreign leader is Pleased with you, they will not mind being asked for a small gift.</French>
	<German>Zufriedene Anführer anderer Zivilisationen kann man ruhig gelegentlich um ein kleines Geschenk bitten.</German>
	<Italian>If a foreign leader is Pleased with you, they will not mind being asked for a small gift.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Si un leader extranjero está Amable contigo, no se opondrán a ser preguntados por un pequeño regalo.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_11</Tag>
	<English>Units led by a warlord can be upgraded for free, and they do not lose their experience points.</English>
	<French>Units led by a warlord can be upgraded for free, and they do not lose their experience points.</French>
	<German>Von Kriegsherren angeführte Einheiten können umsonst modernisiert werden und verlieren dabei auch keine Erfahrungspunkte.</German>
	<Italian>Units led by a warlord can be upgraded for free, and they do not lose their experience points.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Las unidades lideradas por un caudillo pueden ser modernizadas gratis, y no perderán sus putnos de experiencia.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- advc.008c: Protecting wounded units is an important point (and
	 "experienced veterans" a tautology) -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_12</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) When a stack of units is attacked, the unit with the best chance of winning will usually defend first - but rookie units will attempt to protect wounded veterans and medics.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) When a stack of units is attacked, the unit with the best chance of winning will usually defend first - but rookie units will attempt to protect wounded veterans and medics.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Wenn ein Einheitenstapel angegriffen wird, verteidigt normalerweise die Einheit mit der besten Siegeschance zuerst - aber grüne Einheiten versuchen verwundete Veteranen und Sanitäter zu beschützen.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) When a stack of units is attacked, the unit with the best chance of winning will usually defend first - but rookie units will attempt to protect wounded veterans and medics.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Cuando una pila de unidades es atacada, la unidad con mejor oprtunidad de ganar será normalmente la que defienda primero - pero las unidades novatas intentarán proteger veteranos experimentados y médicos.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_13</Tag>
	<English>In the city build queue, use [CTRL] and [SHIFT] to move items up and down; and [ALT] to toggle whether or not items should repeat.</English>
	<French>In the city build queue, use [CTRL] and [SHIFT] to move items up and down; and [ALT] to toggle whether or not items should repeat.</French>
	<German>In der Bauauftragsliste einer Stadt können [Strg] und [Umschalt] benutzt werden, um Einträge hoch und runter zu bewegen, und [Alt] um Einträge endlos bauen zu lassen.</German>
	<Italian>In the city build queue, use [CTRL] and [SHIFT] to move items up and down; and [ALT] to toggle whether or not items should repeat.</Italian>
	<Spanish>En la cola de construcción, usa [CTRL] y [MAYÚS] para mover objetos arriba y abajo; y [ALT] para alternar si los objetos deben repetirse o no.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- replacement text for the inaccurate barbarian tip (changed english and german only)-->
<!-- advc.008c: Replacement text had been invalidated by advc.300. Now the
	 original hint ("Barbarians can appear anywhere a tile is obscured by fog
	 of war, so never assume a tile you can't see is safe, even if you checked
	 it the turn before!") is correct again. I'm overwriting hint 14 instead
	 because it's bad advice: "Be careful in signing Open Border agreements -
	 make sure your 'friend' isn't mapping out your land for sale to the 
	 highest bidder!" -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_14</Tag>
	<English>Barbarians do not appear in tiles that are visible to any civilization. Carefully positioned lookouts can significantly reduce the barbarian activity in an area.</English>
	<French>Les barbares peuvent appara&#238;tre sur toutes les cases recouvertes par le brouillard de guerre. Vous ne saurez donc jamais ce qu'il y a sur celles qui sont invisibles, m&#234;me si vous avez d&#233;j&#224; v&#233;rifi&#233; au tour pr&#233;c&#233;dent !</French>
	<German>Barbaren erscheinen nicht auf Feldern, die von einer Zivilisation eingesehen werden können. Wohl positionierte Späher können die Barbarenaktivität in einem Gebiet deutlich verringern.</German>
	<Italian>I Barbari possono apparire in un qualsiasi spazio oscurato dalla nebbia di guerra. Non essere mai certo che uno spazio non visibile sia sicuro, anche se hai controllato durante il turno precedente!</Italian>
	<Spanish>Los bárbaros no reaparecerán en dos pasos de cualquiera de las unidades. Con el posicionamiento cuidadoso de batidores puedes bloquear completamente grupos de pillaje que se formen en tu área.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<!-- replacement text for the double-click tip, because I've changed the functionality of double-click -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_6</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) Double clicking on a stack of units will wake them all up.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) Double clicking on a stack of units will wake them all up.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Ein Doppelklick auf einen Einheitenstapel weckt sie alle auf.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) Double clicking on a stack of units will wake them all up.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Doble click en una pila de unidades las despertará a todas.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_14</Tag>
	<English>(K-Mod) Hold the [X] key when issuing a command to temporarily suppress automatic unit cycling.</English>
	<French>(K-Mod) Hold the [X] key when issuing a command to temporarily suppress automatic unit cycling.</French>
	<German>(K-Mod) Halten Sie [X] gedrückt, um den automatischen Einheitenwechsel zu unterdrücken.</German>
	<Italian>(K-Mod) Hold the [X] key when issuing a command to temporarily suppress automatic unit cycling.</Italian>
	<Spanish>(K-Mod) Mantener la tecla [X] presionada cuando das una órden para suprimir temporalmente el ciclo de unidades.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_15</Tag>
	<English>Commerce sliders and espionage weights can be set to max/min quickly by right clicking their +/- buttons.</English>
	<French>Commerce sliders and espionage weights can be set to max/min quickly by right clicking their +/- buttons.</French>
	<German>Die Handelsraten und Spinonagegewichtungen können durch einen Rechtsklick auf die Plus- oder Minusknöpfe schnell maximiert beziehungsweise minimiert werden.</German>
	<Italian>Commerce sliders and espionage weights can be set to max/min quickly by right clicking their +/- buttons.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Commerce sliders and espionage weights can be set to max/min quickly by right clicking their +/- buttons.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- k146: I've changed the wording a little and added the German translation.
	 -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_KMOD_HINT_16</Tag>
	<English>Hold [ALT] when clicking the 'Wake' command in order to wake all your units of the same type around the world.</English>
	<French>Hold [ALT] when clicking the 'Wake' command in order to wake all your units of the same type around the world.</French>
	<German>Halten Sie beim Wecken einer Einheit [ALT] gedrückt, so werden weltweit alle Ihre Einheiten dieses Typs geweckt.</German>
	<Italian>Hold [ALT] when clicking the 'Wake' command in order to wake all your units of the same type around the world.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Hold [ALT] when clicking the 'Wake' command in order to wake all your units of the same type around the world.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Thought it'd be nice to mention the small K-Mod change to
	 fortified Spies. Overwrites the value in CIV4GameText_BTS.xml -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_51</Tag>
	<English>Good things come to spies who wait. Leaving a spy on a tile will reduce the costs of all Espionage Missions performed in that tile. If you fortify a Spy in a foreign tile, it will wake up once mission costs are maximally reduced.</English>
	<French>Un espion patient est toujours r&#233;compens&#233;. Si vous laissez un espion sur une case, cela r&#233;duira le co&#251;t de toutes les missions d'espionnage lanc&#233;es contre les &#233;l&#233;ments dans cette case. Si vous laissez un espion dans une ville &#233;trang&#232;re, vos missions dans cette ville vous co&#251;teront donc bien moins cher.</French>
	<German>Gut Ding will Weile haben - das gilt auch f&#252;r Spione. Je l&#228;nger sich ein Spion auf einem Gel&#228;ndefeld aufh&#228;lt, desto geringer werden die Kosten f&#252;r Spionagemissionen auf diesem Feld. Wenn Sie einen Spion auf einem gegnerischen Feld verschanzen, meldet er sich, wenn die Missionskosten maximal gesenkt sind.</German>
	<Italian>La spia migliore &#232; quella che sa aspettare. Lasciando una spia su una casella riduce i costi di tutte le missioni di spionaggio verso quella casella. Perci&#242;, lasciando una spia in una citt&#224; nemica, le missioni verso di questa costeranno meno.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Los esp&#237;as que saben esperar tienen sus ventajas. Dejar un esp&#237;a en una casilla reducir&#225; los costes de todas las misiones de espionaje realizadas contra los objetos de dicha casilla. Por tanto, dejar un esp&#237;a en una ciudad enemiga abaratar&#225; significativamente el coste de tus misiones en dicha ciudad.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Let's not be so dramatic about enemy spies -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_52</Tag>
	<English>If you spend more Espionage Points than an opponent, your missions towards that opponent get cheaper. Every point you spend throughout the game is added to this total. By increasing your Espionage spending, you also make it costlier for rivals to conduct missions against you.</English>
	<French>Si vous d&#233;pensez plus de points d'espionnage qu'un de vos adversaires, vos missions contre lui vous co&#251;teront moins cher. Chaque point d&#233;pens&#233; dans le jeu est totalis&#233;, alors si vous avez un rival acharn&#233; qui d&#233;pense plus de points d'espionnage que vous, vous avez int&#233;r&#234;t &#224; augmenter vos d&#233;penses d'espionnage.</French>
	<German>Wenn Sie mehr Spionagepunkte als eine gegnerische Zivilisation einsetzen, sinken die Kosten f&#252;r Missionen gegen diesen Gegner. Jeder Punkt, den Sie im Laufe des Spiels ausgeben, z&#228;hlt zu diesr Gesamtsumme. Und je mehr Spionagepunkte Sie einsetzen, desto kostspieliger werden Missionen gegen Sie.</German>
	<Italian>Se spendi un maggior numero di punti spionaggio di un avversario, le tue missioni nei suoi confronti diventeranno pi&#249; economiche. Ogni punto che spendi durante la partita viene aggiunto a questo totale, perci&#242; se vedi un avversario che ti surclassa in punti spionaggio, &#232; una mossa saggia aumentare la spesa in questo senso.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Si gastas m&#225;s puntos de espionaje que un rival, tus misiones contra dicho adversario ser&#225;n m&#225;s baratas. Cada punto que gastes a lo largo de la partida se suma a este total, de modo que si ves que un duro rival gasta m&#225;s que t&#250; en puntos de espionaje, es buena idea aumentar tu gasto en espionaje.</Spanish>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_63</Tag>
	<English>If you are vexed by enemy spies, consider placing a Spy unit in each of your border cities.</English>
	<French>Gardez quelques espions &#224; l'int&#233;rieur de vos fronti&#232;res pour le contre-espionnage. Les espions ennemis peuvent faire des ravages !</French>
	<German>Wenn feindliche Spione Ihnen &#196;rger bereiten, erw&#228;gen Sie, eigene Spione in einigen Ihrer Grenzst&#228;dte zu stationieren.</German>
	<Italian>Tieni alcune spie all'interno dei tuoi confini per effettuare il controspionaggio. Le spie nemiche possono scatenare il caos!</Italian>
	<Spanish>Mant&#233;n algunos esp&#237;as en tus fronteras para practicar el contraespionaje. &#161;Los esp&#237;as enemigos pueden sembrar el caos!</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Nudge players toward disabling Random Events -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_69</Tag>
	<English>If you play with the Random Events option, you may be wise to keep some reserve gold in your treasury. Your savings could help mitigate the effects of a disastrous event or grant you access to additional opportunities when a positive event rolls around.</English>
	<French>Faites en sorte de ne pas dilapider votre tr&#233;sor. Vos &#233;conomies pourraient un jour vous aider &#224; att&#233;nuer les effets d'un &#233;v&#232;nement catastrophique ou vous donner acc&#232;s &#224; de nouvelles opportunit&#233;s si un &#233;v&#232;nement positif devait survenir .</French>
	<German>Wenn Sie mit Zufallsereignissen spielen, kann es klug sein, ein paar Goldreserven in der Schatzkammer zu belassen. Das Ersparte kann helfen, die Auswirkungen eines verheerenden Ereignisses zu mildern, oder Ihnen zusätzliche Möglichkeiten bei einem positiven Ereignis verschaffen.</German>
	<Italian>Potrebbe essere saggio tenere una riserva d'oro nel tuo tesoro. Non si può mai sapere quando potrebbe rendersi necessario mitigare gli effetti di un evento catastrofico, o quando una serie positiva di eventi potrebbe permetterti di accedere ad altre opportunità.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Debes ser prudente y guardar algunas reservas de oro en tu tesoro. Nunca se sabe cuándo tus ahorros pueden servir para mitigar los efectos de un suceso desastroso o para darte acceso a oportunidades adicionales cuando se produzca un suceso positivo.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c, advc.002g: It's good to point out the BtS Concepts page, but
	 since it's no longer a novelty, the players don't need to "be sure to
	 check" it out. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_59</Tag>
	<English>The "BtS Concepts" page in the Civilopedia summarizes the changes introduced by the "Beyond the Sword" expansion.</English>
	<French>Pensez &#224; lire la page "Concepts de BtS" dans la Civilop&#233;die pour conna&#238;tre toutes les modifications apport&#233;es par cette extension.</French>
	<German>Die Seite "BtS-Konzepte" in der Zivilop&#228;die fasst die &#196;nderungen der "Beyond the Sword"-Erweiterung zusammen.</German>
	<Italian>Consulta la pagina "Nozioni di BtS" nella Civilopedia per leggere tutte le modifiche effettuate in questa espansione.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Aseg&#250;rate de consultar la p&#225;gina "Conceptos de BtS" en la Civilopedia para conocer todos los cambios que incorpora esta expansi&#243;n.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Removed "now" as it's longer news. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_56</Tag>
	<English>Intercontinental trade routes yield more gold than normal trade routes. Build a Customs House to further cash in.</English>
	<French>Les routes commerciales intercontinentales rapportent d&#233;sormais plus d'or que les routes commerciales normales. Construisez un poste de douane pour augmenter encore vos recettes.</French>
	<German>Interkontinentale Handelswege erwirtschaften mehr Gold als normale Handelswege. Errichten Sie f&#252;r zus&#228;tzliche Einnahmen ein Zollamt.</German>
	<Italian>Le rotte commerciali intercontinentali producono pi&#249; oro di quelle normali. Costruisci delle dogane per aumentare gli introiti.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Las rutas comerciales intercontinentales reportan m&#225;s oro que las rutas comerciales normales. Construye una aduana para aumentar los ingresos obtenidos.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: An opportunity to point out Civ4lerts. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_13</Tag>
	<English>Check the foreign advisor often - knowing what your friends (and foes) can offer in trade is valuable information. The BUG mod can alert you whenever a technology or resource becomes available for trade; see the "Alerts" tab of the BUG menu.</English>
	<French>Consultez souvent votre conseiller diplomatique. Il est essentiel de savoir ce que vos amis (et vos ennemis) peuvent vous proposer.</French>
	<German>Werfen Sie regelm&#228;&#223;ig einen Blick auf den Auslandsberater. Schlie&#223;lich m&#252;ssen Sie wissen, womit Ihre Freunde (und Feinde) handeln. Sie k&#246;nnen sich benachrichtigen lassen, wenn ein Gegner neue Technologien oder Ressourcen anbietet. Klicken Sie dazu im BUG-Mod-Men&#252; auf den Reiter "Warnungen".</German>
	<Italian>Consulta spesso il consigliere degli esteri per sapere chi tra gli amici (o i nemici) &#232; in grado di fornire informazioni in cambio di qualcosa.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Consultad con frecuencia al consejero de Asuntos Exteriores. Saber lo que vuestros amigos (y enemigos) pueden ofreceros en intercambio es una informaci&#243;n valiosa.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Another one that needs to be less emphatic -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_15</Tag>
	<English>Walls and castles help protect your cities in the first half of the game, but after gunpowder, only city culture boosts your defenses.</English>
	<French>Ne n&#233;gligez pas la culture de votre empire. Remparts et ch&#226;teaux ne sont efficaces que jusqu'&#224; l'arriv&#233;e de la poudre &#224; canon, mais une grande influence culturelle am&#233;liore les d&#233;fenses &#224; toutes les &#233;poques.</French>
	<German>Mauern und Schl&#246;sser sch&#252;tzen Ihre St&#228;dte in der ersten Spielh&#228;lfte, aber nach Erfindung des Schie&#223;pulvers st&#228;rkt nur Kultur den Verteidigungswert Ihrer St&#228;dte.</German>
	<Italian>Non trascurare la cultura del tuo impero: mura e castelli dureranno soltanto fino alla scoperta della polvere da sparo, ma una grande influenza culturale aumenter&#224; le difese in tutte le epoche.</Italian>
	<Spanish>No descuid&#233;is la cultura de vuestro imperio. Las murallas y castillos solo valdr&#225;n hasta que aparezca la p&#243;lvora, pero una gran influencia cultural mejorar&#225; las defensas en todas las &#233;pocas.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: The part about "espionage benefits" may have referred to
	 visibility from religion. Not worth mentioning with BtS. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_26</Tag>
	<English>Open Borders agreements are invitations for your missionaries - if you spread your state religion widely enough, your neighbors may convert to your faith, which greatly improves diplomatic relations.</English>
	<French>Les accords de libre passage sont des invitations pour vos missionnaires : propagez rapidement votre religion d'&#233;tat pour profiter des avantages de l'espionnage ! Si votre religion se propage suffisamment, vos voisins se convertiront peut-&#234;tre &#224; votre foi, ce qui peut am&#233;liorer vos relations.</French>
	<German>Offene Grenzen sind eine Einladung an Ihre Missionare. Wenn Sie Ihre Staatsreligion weit genug verbreiten, nehmen Ihre Nachbarn diese m&#246;glicherweise an, wodurch sich die Beziehungen zu Ihrer Zivilisation deutlich verbessern.</German>
	<Italian>Il diritto di passaggio &#232; un invito per i tuoi missionari: diffondi la religione ufficiale rapidamente e trai vantaggio dallo spionaggio!</Italian>
	<Spanish>Los acuerdos de apertura de fronteras son una invitaci&#243;n para vuestros misioneros. Propagad vuestra religi&#243;n oficial r&#225;pidamente y aprovechad los beneficios que os ofrece el espionaje. Si vuestra religi&#243;n se propaga lo suficiente, los vecinos pueden convertirse a vuestra fe, lo que puede mejorar vuestras relaciones.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Wall and Castle aren't good examples; suggests that these
	 should normally be built. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_27</Tag>
	<English>Make sure you need every building your city creates. Cities bringing in no research can sometimes skip Libraries, just as cities that don't train units can skip Barracks.</English>
	<French>Ne construisez que les b&#226;timents dont vos villes ont besoin. Celles qui ne produisent pas de commerce peuvent se passer de biblioth&#232;que, celles qui ne verront jamais le combat n'ont besoin ni de remparts ni de ch&#226;teaux.</French>
	<German>Achten Sie darauf, nur Geb&#228;ude zu errichten, die Ihre Stadt auch wirklich braucht. Bei geringem Forschungsertrag brauchen Sie nicht unbedingt eine Bibliothek, und Städte, die keine Einheiten trainieren, kommen ohne Kaserne aus.</German>
	<Italian>Assicurati di aver davvero bisogno degli edifici che costruisci: le citt&#224; che non generano commercio possono fare a meno delle biblioteche, cos&#236; come una citt&#224; che non viene mai attaccata pu&#242; rinunciare a mura e castello.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Aseguraos de que todos los edificios que se hagan en vuestras ciudades sean necesarios. Las ciudades que no reporten comercio pueden prescindir de las bibliotecas, del mismo modo que aqu&#233;llas que nunca ver&#225;n una batalla pueden prescindir de las murallas y el castillo.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Inconsistent capitilization, and the button isn't called
	 "Colony". -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_54</Tag>
	<English>To reduce your city maintenance, consider turning your cities on distant continents into colonies. To form a colony, go to the Domestic Advisor screen and press the button with the fist icon.</English>
	<French>Si vous cherchez &#224; r&#233;duire le co&#251;t d'entretien de vos villes, pensez &#224; transformer en colonies vos villes situ&#233;es sur des continents lointains. Pour former une colonie, ouvrez l'&#233;cran du conseiller aux affaires int&#233;rieures et cliquez sur le bouton "Colonie".</French>
	<German>Um Ihre Unterhaltskosten f&#252;r St&#228;dte zu senken, k&#246;nnen Sie Ihre St&#228;dte auf entfernten Kontinenten in Kolonien umwandeln. &#214;ffnen Sie dazu den Inlandsberater und klicken Sie auf den Knopf mit dem Faustsymbol.</German>
	<Italian>Se stai cercando di ridurre i costi di manutenzione della tua citt&#224;, considera di trasformare quelle lontane in Colonie. Per formare una Colonia, vai nella schermata del consigliere interno e seleziona la voce "Colonia".</Italian>
	<Spanish>Si quieres reducir los costes de mantenimiento de tus ciudades, considera la posibilidad de convertir en colonias las que est&#233;n situadas en continentes lejanos. Para formar una colonia, ve a la pantalla del Consejero de Interior y selecciona el bot&#243;n "Colonia".</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Weird capitalization; and clarified the "not only
	 resources" part. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_36</Tag>
	<English>Grains, livestock, and seafood not only provide resources to your city network, but also rich yields to the local city. Cities placed near two or more of these food sources will grow quickly!</English>
	<French>Les c&#233;r&#233;ales, le b&#233;tail et les fruits de mer fournissent non seulement des ressources mais permettent &#233;galement d'enrichir la ville qui les produit. Les villes fond&#233;es pr&#232;s de deux telles sources de nourriture ou plus se d&#233;veloppent rapidement !</French>
	<German>Getreide, Vieh und Meeresfr&#252;chte sind nicht nur handelbare Ressourcen, sie steigern auch deutlich die &#214;rtlichen Ertr&#228;ge. St&#228;dte mit zwei oder mehr solcher Nahrungsquellen wachsen schnell!</German>
	<Italian>Grano, bestiame e frutti di mare forniscono risorse e ricchezza alle citt&#224; vicine. Le citt&#224; vicine ad almeno due di queste risorse cresceranno rapidamente!</Italian>
	<Spanish>El grano, el ganado y los productos del mar no solo proporcionan recursos, sino que aportan riqueza a la ciudad. Las ciudades situadas cerca de dos o m&#225;s de esos recursos crecer&#225;n r&#225;pidamente.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Changed "foes" to "rivals". -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_24</Tag>
	<English>Watch for announcements about religions being founded and wonders being completed - this can give you a hint as to how advanced your rivals are.</English>
	<French>Soyez attentifs aux messages annon&#231;ant la fondation de nouvelles religions ou la construction de merveilles. Ils peuvent vous renseigner sur la progression de vos ennemis.</French>
	<German>Achten Sie auf Nachrichten &#252;ber neue Religionen und Wunder - daraus kann sich ableiten lassen, wie fortschrittlich Ihre Gegner sind.</German>
	<Italian>Tieni d'occhio gli annunci sulla fondazione di nuove religioni o sul completamento di una Meraviglia: cos&#236; facendo, potrai farti un'idea dei progressi dei tuoi avversari.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Mirad los avisos de fundaci&#243;n de religiones y realizaci&#243;n de maravillas, pues os pueden dar una pista sobre lo avanzados que van los rivales.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: To say that barbs can appear "anywhere" in the fog of war
	 is a bit misleading. Removed that part. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_12</Tag>
	<English>If a tile is presently obscured by fog of war, Barbarians can appear there. Don't assume a tile you can't see is safe, even if you've checked it last turn!</English>
	<French>Les barbares peuvent appara&#238;tre sur toutes les cases recouvertes par le brouillard de guerre. Vous ne saurez donc jamais ce qu'il y a sur celles qui sont invisibles, m&#234;me si vous avez d&#233;j&#224; v&#233;rifi&#233; au tour pr&#233;c&#233;dent !</French>
	<German>Im Nebel des Krieges k&#246;nnen Barbaren lauern. Gehen Sie nicht davon aus, dass ein verh&#252;lltes Feld sicher ist ... selbst wenn Sie es im vorigen Zug erst &#252;berpr&#252;ft haben!</German>
	<Italian>I Barbari possono apparire in un qualsiasi spazio oscurato dalla nebbia di guerra. Non essere mai certo che uno spazio non visibile sia sicuro, anche se hai controllato durante il turno precedente!</Italian>
	<Spanish>Los b&#225;rbaros pueden aparecer en cualquier lugar en el que una casilla est&#233; oscurecida por la niebla de la guerra, as&#237; que no supong&#225;is que una casilla que no pod&#225;is ver es segura, aunque la hay&#225;is comprobado en el turno anterior.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Added Explorers. Was "Entering native villages with scouts will
	 produce better results..." -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_1</Tag>
	<English>Scouts and Explorers get better results from tribal villages than other units.</English>
	<French>Envoyez des &#233;claireurs dans les villages indig&#232;nes pour obtenir de meilleurs r&#233;sultats.</French>
	<German>Betreten Sie Stammesd&#246;rfer mit einem Sp&#228;her oder Kundschafter, um bessere Ergebnisse zu erzielen.</German>
	<Italian>Si ottengono migliori risultati entrando nei villaggi indigeni con gli scout.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Dar&#225; mejores resultados entrar en las aldeas de los nativos con batidores.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: "More great people will appear in cities that build ancient
	 wonders or multiple great wonders." ??
	 Whether they're ancient doesn't matter (it might matter for the culture
	 output, but not for GPP). Perhaps they meant "a great wonder or multiple
	 national wonders", which is what the German version says.
	 I've just removed that part in the English version. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_41</Tag>
	<English>Wonders of the World not only provide unique benefits, they also inspire your populace. More great people will appear in cities that build Wonders.</English>
	<French>Les merveilles vous apportent non seulement des avantages uniques, mais inspirent &#233;galement votre population. Plus de personnages illustres feront leur apparition dans les villes h&#233;bergeant des merveilles anciennes ou multiples.</French>
	<German>Wunder haben einzigartige Vorteile und inspirieren Ihre Untertanen. Aus diesem Grund bringen St&#228;dte, in denen Sie Weltwunder oder Nationale Wunder errichten, mehr Gro&#223;e Pers&#246;nlichkeiten hervor.</German>
	<Italian>Le Meraviglie del mondo non solo forniscono dei benefici molto utili, ma sono anche una fonte di ispirazione per la tua popolazione. Nelle citt&#224; in cui si trovano delle Grandi Meraviglie &#232; pi&#249; facile che appaiano dei Grandi Personaggi.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Las maravillas del mundo no solo proporcionan beneficios &#250;nicos, sino que tambi&#233;n son una inspiraci&#243;n para el pueblo. En las ciudades que construyan maravillas de la antig&#252;edad o varias grandes maravillas aparecer&#225;n m&#225;s grandes personajes.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Shortened this a bit -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_67</Tag>
	<English>While the HQ of a corporation generates extra income, each city hosting a corporation branch suffers increased maintenance costs. Unless you build Courthouses in your branch cities and a Bank in the HQ city, you may actually run at a net loss.</English>
	<French>Si vous choisissez de fonder une soci&#233;t&#233; commerciale, sachez que m&#234;me si le si&#232;ge social b&#233;n&#233;ficiera de revenus suppl&#233;mentaires, chaque ville abritant cette soci&#233;t&#233; subira une hausse de ses co&#251;ts d'entretien. Construisez des tribunaux dans toutes ces villes et des banques pr&#232;s de vos si&#232;ges sociaux, sous peine de subir une banqueroute.</French>
	<German>Ein Unternehmenssitz liefert zwar Zusatzeinnahmen, aber gleichzeitig verursachen die Niederlassungen Unterhaltskosten. Errichten Sie in Städten mit Niederlassungen Gerichtsgebäude und in der Stadt mit dem Unternehmenssitz eine Bank, um nicht unterm Strich einen Verlust zu machen.</German>
	<Italian>Se decidi di fondare una Corporazione, ricorda che sebbene i quartieri generali beneficeranno di rendite extra, ogni città che ospita una corporazione vedrà aumentare i suoi costi di mantenimento. Costruisci Palazzi di giustizia nelle città con le Corporazioni e Banche nei quartieri generali, altrimenti la Corporazione potrebbe andare in passivo.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Si eliges fundar una corporación, recuerda que -aunque sus sedes gocen de beneficios extra- toda ciudad que albergue una corporación tendrá mayores costes de mantenimiento. Construye delegaciones en todas tus ciudades con corporaciones y bancos en tus sedes; de otro modo, la corporación no hará más que generar pérdidas.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Said "ALT-I" (instead of plus), which was confusing. Improved
	 German translation. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_2</Tag>
	<English>Press [CTRL + I] to play with a minimized interface. Press [ALT + I] to play without interface.</English>
	<French>Appuyez sur [CTRL + I] pour jouer avec une interface r&#233;duite. Appuyez sur [ALT + I] pour jouer sans interface.</French>
	<German>Dr&#252;cken Sie [STRG + I], um die Bedienoberfläche zu minimieren oder [ALT + I], um sie ganz auszublenden.</German>
	<Italian>Premi [CTRL + I] per giocare con l'interfaccia minimizzata. Premi [ALT + I] per giocare senza interfaccia.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Pulsar [CTRL + I] para jugar con una interfaz minimizada. Pulsar [ALT + I] para jugar sin interfaz.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

<!-- advc.008c: Info about Alt key added. -->
<TEXT>
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_39</Tag>
	<English>To view combat odds, hold down the right mouse button on the target tile. By also holding down [ALT], you can view combat odds even when not at war.</English>
	<French>Pour conna&#238;tre vos chances en cas de combat, maintenez le bouton droit de la souris enfonc&#233; sur la case vis&#233;e.</French>
	<German>Um die Kampfchancen Ihrer Einheit zu sehen, halten Sie die rechte Maustaste über dem Zielfeld gedrückt. Wenn Sie außerdem [ALT] gedrückt halten, werden die Kampfchancen auch dann angezeigt, wenn Sie nicht im Krieg sind.</German>
	<Italian>Per visualizzare le probabilit&#224; di vittoria di uno scontro, tieni premuto il pulsante destro del mouse su una casella bersaglio.</Italian>
	<Spanish>Mantener el cursor encima de la casilla objetivo para ver las probabilidades del combate.</Spanish>
</TEXT>

</Civ4GameText>
